chalk.com 2018-10-08

# Privacy Policy | Chalk

At Chalk.com Education Inc., doing business as Chalk, your right to privacy is very important to us. We provide you with the ability to create, share, edit, access, manage, print, provide feedback on or have conversations about lesson plans, assessments, curriculum, standards, and assessment results (the “Service”). We collect certain specific information from you, and we also automatically collect information and data relating to the usage of our services by all our users, including you which provides us with aggregate data that Chalk uses to improve the Services. Because we are committed to protecting your privacy rights and the information you provide to us, we have developed this privacy policy. It explains how we will protect your information and describes how we will use and share it.

This policy is concerned with the protection of your personal information only. Personal information includes any data that can be used to identify you as an individual, such as your name, e-mail address, income, personal opinion, interests, home contact information, identification numbers, user IDs, passwords, ethnic origin, and age. Under Canadian law, in a business context, personal information does not include the name, job title, business address, or business telephone number of any employee in an organization.

Additionally, Chalk automatically logs IP addresses, session sources, and other data which tracks users’ access to the Services. We analyze these logs for sales and marketing purposes as well as system performance monitoring. These logs are analyzed for the aggregate trends they reveal about our customers and how the customers use the Services. We may also collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service and to understand more about the demographics of our users.

Chalk may use aggregated personal information to determine the demographic composition of our user base and to distribute statistics and general marketplace information about Chalk. This aggregate information does not identify specific users.

This policy describes the following practices:

  * Collecting your personal information
  * Use of your personal information
  * Sharing your personal information
  * Maintaining your personal information

This privacy policy may change from time to time to reflect Chalk’s internal needs, customer feedback, or changes in applicable privacy legislation. Chalk will post all such changes on our website, so please visit this page regularly.

## Collecting your personal information

In order to use the services provided by Chalk, you will be required to provide specific information about yourself, such as your name and e-mail address for some solutions and address, telephone number and financial or credit card information for others in order to access and use the Services. We will always inform you when we need information that personally identifies you, and we will keep this information in strict confidence. Additionally, you may, on occasion, voluntarily provide Chalk with information that can be classified as personal information – all such personal information will be stored and maintained in accordance with this privacy policy.

As an education technology company servicing the K-12 grades, among others, Chalk relies on a teacher, school, or school district to obtain verifiable parental consent to provide our services to under-16 users. We may collect an under-16 user’s name (first name and last name), e-mail address and/or student ID in order to operate and provide the Services, and we may collect the under-16 user’s parent’s (or legal guardian’s) e-mail address in order to provide notice to the child’s parent or guardian that we may contact the under-16 user for the purpose of allowing access to and use of the Services.

We collect information about you in the following ways:

### As part of your registration for Chalk’s software and services

We will require your name and e-mail at minimum as well as address, telephone number and credit card information for billing purposes, and you will also be provided with a user ID and a password, or the ability to create a user ID and/or password. This information is kept confidential and stored securely by Chalk.

### As part of your educational institution using Chalk’s software and services

We will require the name and student ID for the individuals you, as a teacher, school, or school district, want to track and manage assessment results for within the Chalk Services. Chalk relies on a teacher, school, or school district to obtain verifiable parental consent to collect and use this information on your behalf.

### Automatically by Chalk’s software and services

Chalk’s software and services contain features that automatically collect information from users, such as viewing times, usage statistics, and other tracking information. Although this information will not identify you personally, it nevertheless provides certain information about you, and we therefore treat it as personal information. Additionally, use of Chalk’s website and/or software may result in the collection of technical information such as your computer’s IP address, operating system, browser name/version, the referring web page, requested page, date/time, and sometimes a “cookie” (which can be disabled using your browser preferences); such information is used to help us understand the overall usage pattern of our website and software.

### As part of your use of Chalk’s software and services

You have the ability to post content and information through Chalk’s services, such as lesson plans, class materials, assessments, conversations, observations or comments and opinions. Please be advised that any personal information that you voluntarily post to any public forum or to any area where third parties may legally access it, will NOT be considered confidential in any way, and Chalk will not have any obligation to protect it in a secured system or obtain your consent to its disclosure, as you will have made the decision to publicly post it. Chalk neither expects nor desires you to include any personal information, whether of yourself or of any third party, in any content that you may post or upload to Chalk’s site, and if you include any such personal information of yourself or any third party, it is your responsibility to obtain all relevant and informed consents to such inclusion. At your request, Chalk will be happy to change, remove, or restrict access to any post or upload made by you (subject to technical feasibility) in order to protect the integrity of personal information included in it, and Chalk also reserves the right to refuse to post, or to delete any posts or uploads, containing such personal information.

### You contact Chalk directly

Customers and business partners often contact us directly. When you contact any Chalk employee by telephone, e-mail, in person, or through our website, you will be asked to provide consent to the collection of personal information if your personal information will help us deliver the information, products, or services you require.

### You respond to communications from Chalk

From time to time, Chalk may invite you to provide us with information for specific purposes. We may ask for this information through feedback features on our website or software; we may send out e-mail inviting feedback or offering products and services; or we may ask you for information concerning support of our products or services. Your response to these communications may require you to submit personal information and opinions.

### Your information is obtained through a third party

Occasionally, Chalk will obtain information about you from third parties, such as mailing list providers, third party service providers, ISPs, or account providers. Third-party providers are responsible for obtaining consent for the release of personal information to us from those individuals identified on mailing lists, surveys, or through other collection methods.

### Your information is obtained through an integration with a third party software provider

Occasionally, Chalk is implemented into an environment where it is integrated with a Student Information System or Learning Management System provided by a third-party software provider. These integrations are to facilitate the transfer of education related data, such as subjects and class enrollment, assessment results, or learning content and may require your personal information to ensure accounts in each system are synchronized. Third-party software providers are responsible for obtaining consent for the release of personal information to us from those individuals through the integrations.

### Third party collection of your information

Where other users post links to third party websites, please be aware that such third parties are not within Chalk’s control or responsibility, and your use or access to those sites may result in third parties collecting information from you. Third party products or services provided through third party websites or applications are not owned or controlled by Chalk, and are governed by the third party’s terms and conditions and/or privacy policy. You are encouraged to read the terms and other policies published by such third parties on their websites or otherwise.

### Information collected through cookies

Cookies are small files that websites place on your computer as you browse the web. Like many websites, Chalk uses cookies to discover how people are using our Services and to make them work better. We use these technologies to deliver, measure, and improve our Services in various ways. These uses generally fall into one of the following categories:

  * Authentication and Security: We will use cookies to help authenticate your access to Chalk, and prevent unauthorized parties from accessing your account
  * Preferences: We will use cookies to remember information about your browser and preferences
  * Analytics and Research: We will use cookies to help us improve and understand how people use our services in order to optimize and improve your experience on Chalk.

Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allow you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of the Services best features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on. Note that the use of cookies by anyone other than Chalk is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over those cookies.

## Use of your personal information

Chalk does not sell or rent any of your personal information to any third-party for any purpose – including for advertising or marketing purposes. Chalk does not share personal information with third-parties except in the limited circumstances set forth in the section “Sharing your personal Information.” Personal information collected from and about students is never used for behaviorally-targeted advertising to students (by us or third-parties). We use the information we collect from you to provide you with the best Chalk experience. More specifically, this information is used to:

  * Allow access to the Service
  * Provide and improve the Service, for example by developing new products and features
  * Respond to your emails, submissions, questions, requests for information or customer support
  * Customize the Service for you, and improve your experience with it
  * Send you information about features on our Service or changes to our policies and Services
  * Help connect you with your students and their parents/guardians within the Service
  * Most crucially, to protect our community by making sure the Service remains safe and secure

We use automatically collected information (described in the “Collecting Information” section above) to provide and support our Service, and for the additional uses described in this section of our Privacy Policy.

## Sharing your personal information

Subject to any exceptions stated above in the collection of information section, should Chalk collect any of your personal information, we will follow these practices regarding the distribution of that information.

### Your personal information is always protected

Chalk uses reasonable precautions to protect your personal information and store it securely. Access to your personal information is restricted to those personnel who need it, and Chalk takes reasonable steps to prevent the unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information.

Chalk only uses and discloses your personal information if it helps us facilitate your needs, improve our products and services, meet legal and regulatory requirements, or — to the limited extent possible — manage our internal business operations. Additionally, if there are any disclosure or use restrictions in your consent to the collection of your personal information, Chalk will abide by those restrictions (subject to the consent exceptions listed below).

For example, your credit card information will only be used to bill you for the services that your have authorized or used. The account information provided as part of your registration for Chalk’s services will only be used to provide you with the services.

Chalk may combine your information with other information into an aggregate form, so your information no longer personally identifies you. We may then disclose the aggregate information to third parties, so they can obtain an overall picture of Chalk’s products, services, customer usage patterns and/or other statistical information.

Finally, Chalk makes use of secure transfer protocols (HTTPS, SFTP, etc.) when communicating between the client (your computer or mobile device) and the server (hosted on Google’s Cloud Platform in the United States) so that your personal information is protected even during transit.

### We only share your information with your consent

Chalk provides your information to third parties only for purposes to which you have consented, and we require such third parties to keep your information confidential.

In a few situations, Chalk may be required to disclose your information without your prior consent. For example, Chalk may disclose your information if we are required to do so by law, or if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to:

  * comply with law or legal process
  * protect and defend our rights and property, or the rights and property of a third party
  * protect against misuse or unauthorized use of any of Chalk’s products, software, services, or other proprietary materials
  * protect the personal safety of any person
  * allow for a change of ownership of Chalk and associated transfer of all personal information to the new owner of Chalk – this does not affect the protection of your information under this Privacy Policy

Chalk will always try to provide you with prior notice of such disclosure; however, such notice may not always be possible or reasonable given the circumstances.

Additionally, the nature of the Services provided requires the routine use of your information in the provision of the Services. Your personal information will only be used to the limited extent necessary to provide the Services that you have requested, and may include the following uses:

  * to allow third party suppliers, vendors, contractors and other parties to provide products and services to us or to you, or to otherwise act on our behalf (this may include, without limitation, our authorization of such third parties to e-mail our users regarding updates, surveys and other inquiries regarding their experience with our software and service); and
  * to allow for advertising and other audits, and surveys to, among other things, validate the size and composition of the users of Chalk’s services, and understand their experience with Chalk’s software and service. This may require, among other things, disclosing your access history and/or disclosing records showing which lesson plans or materials were viewed or used by which users.

### Sharing your information through an integration with a third party software provider

Occasionally, Chalk is implemented into an environment where it is integrated with a Student Information System or Learning Management System provided by a third-party software provider. These integrations are to facilitate the transfer of education related data, such as subjects and class enrollment, assessment results, or learning content and may require your personal information to ensure accounts in each system are synchronized. Your consent to use the Service includes consent for any third-party software provider to receive your personal information from us to enable those integrations.

## Maintaining your personal information

Chalk has established the following practices regarding the maintenance of your personal information.

### You can request access to your personal information at any time

If, for any reason, you wish to review your personal information that Chalk has in its possession, you can contact our Privacy Officer, who will be pleased to provide you with all your personal information that Chalk has on file.

### You can request changes to your personal information at any time

Sometimes, it will be necessary for you to update your personal information Chalk has on file. For example, if you move or change credit cards, you must update your information in order to keep receiving the services provided by Chalk.

If you wish to make any changes or corrections to your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer who will implement the changes. This will help us ensure our records are always up-to-date.

### You can opt out of communications at any time

Additionally, you always have the choice of whether you wish to receive information – such as e-mail updates – from Chalk. In some cases, you may do so simply by changing your preferences on Chalk’s site.

If you do choose to opt out of communications respecting products and services provided by Chalk, you may not obtain all the benefits we could otherwise provide, such as updates or warnings. Chalk will not have any liability to you for your loss of those benefits or any negative effects respecting your use of Chalk’s products or services.

### You can revoke your consent at any time

You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us as described in the “Contacting our Privacy Officer” section below. If you do choose to revoke your consent for the collection of and use of your personal information Chalk will remove that information from its systems. This may result in your inability to make use of the Services entirely.

All content and non-identifiable information, including aggregate data which includes your data, will be maintained as it does not identify specific individuals.

### You can request that your personal information be destroyed at any time

A situation may arise where you desire to have all of your personal information that is contained in Chalk’s records deleted or destroyed. If this is what you wish, please contact our Privacy Officer, who will take care of removing your personal information from all of Chalk’s records. However, there may be situations where we are obligated to retain one archival copy of your information to allow us to comply with laws or respond to legal processes. We will inform you of all such situations, and will only use your retained personal information to the limited extent necessary to comply with such laws or respond to legal processes.

## Contacting our Privacy Officer

Chalk welcomes your comments about this privacy policy, and we would be happy to provide any additional information you require. Please contact our Privacy Officer at [support@chalk.com](mailto:support@chalk.com)

 _This privacy policy supplements any agreements you already have with Chalk, such as your User Agreement or website terms and conditions. Our privacy policy does not replace the terms of those agreements. By agreeing to those terms and using Chalk’s website, products, software and services, you are consenting to the collection and use of your personal information by Chalk in accordance with this privacy policy. This policy was written in accordance with the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA)._
